欢迎加入OCR小组 qq群906722936 字幕优先发布于群内
你相信我吗
Do you trust me?
我得让她远离我
I need to get her away from me.
我在美国找到位外科医生 也许
I found a surgeon in the States who might be
能帮上忙 因为我帮不了
able to help because I can't.
终于要成真了
It's finally fucking happening.
我已经有一首歌了
I already have a song.
我挑了第一首
I picked out the first one.
《暖暖内含光》
"May There Always Be Sunshine. "
安德烈斯
Anders.
不要为了麻烦而让自己惹祸上身
Don't bring trouble down on yourself for the sake of trouble.
你第一次联系我的时候 我很谨慎
I was wary when you first reached out to me.
某些道德准则注定就是要被打破的
Some ethical rules are meant to be breached,
尤其是在为真理服务的时候
especially in service of the truth.
尤利娅跟你问好
Yulia sends her greetings.
她带着新气管回家了
She's back home with her new trachea.
不对劲
Something's not right.
好痛
It hurts.
他在杀人
He's killing people.
也许吧 但归根结底
Maybe, but at the end of the day,
你并没有证据证明你的说法
you don't have any proof of what you're claiming.
是有人要来审问我吗
Is somebody going to interrogate me?
-怎么了  -这边
- What's up? - This way.
去哪里
This way where?
到底怎么回事
What the hell is going on here?
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
你甚至都没有合理依据
You don't even have reasonable grounds.
去跟你们局长说去
Speak to your Police Master.
要不我就直接打给检察机关了
Or I can call the Prosecution Authority directly.
我现在就要带他们出去
But I am taking them out. Now.
什么都别说 明白吗
Don't say a word, okay?
走了
Let's go.
你起很早啊
You're up early.
我约了奥布里
I'm meeting Aubrey.
她爸爸是一起吗
And her dad?
是
Yeah.
要我陪你走过去吗
Do you want me to walk with you?
不用了
No.
行吧 在学校过得开心哦
Okay, well, have a great day at school.
我爱你
I love you.
也爱你
Love you too.
靠
Holy shit.
我去
已提出申诉
A claim has been made- -
内部保密的违规行为
a breach of internal confidentiality.
这话什么意思
What does that even mean?
他们声称我们共享了
They're claiming we shared privileged
患者的保密信息
patient information.
他们是谁
Who the hell is they?
现在 他们就是警方
Well, right now, they are the police.
到目前为止 还没提出任何指控
So far, no charges have been filed.
但他们都没审问我们啊
But they didn't even question us.
不代表以后不会
That doesn't mean they won't.
他们把我们关在警局关了一整宿
They held us in a fucking police station overnight
就因为医患保密协议这事
over doctor- patient confidentiality?
这事在瑞典是犯罪行为
Which is a criminal act in Sweden.
你可能会坐牢的
You could face prison time.
这就是个笑话
This is a joke.
你为什么这么不当回事
Why are you so goddamn breezy?
因为安娜说得对呀 这就是个笑话
Because Ana is right. This is a joke.
我们的过程无可非议
Our process was beyond reproach.
我们拿到了患者家属许可
We had permission from the patients'families.
对患者姓名和身份数据保持匿名
We kept names and identifying data anonymous.
他们没理由指控我们
They don't have a case against us.
你好像不明白
You don't seem to understand.
你说得对 内森
You're right, Nathan.
他们刚把你们扔警局里关了一宿
They just held you in a fucking police station overnight.
你把报告发给了卡罗林斯卡的13名
You sent your report to 13 board members
董事会成员 交了出去 还提供了纸质副本
at Karolinska, handed it over, hard copies.
你以为这些信息是怎么
How the hell do you think that info landed
落到警方手里的
in the hands of the police?
在我看来卡罗林斯卡想让你闭嘴
It seems to me Karolinska wants you silenced.
这些都是恐吓战术 赫德利以前也这么干过
These are scare tactics. Hedley tried this before.
这些可不止是恐吓那么简单
They're not just scare tactics.
这可援引了正式法律条文
There are real laws cited here.
如果他们想找点由头起诉你
If they want to find something to charge you with,
那肯定是能找到的
they'll find it.
那我们会赢的
And we would win.
即便你能赢
Even if you do win,
如果必须的话 卡罗林斯卡这样的机构
an institution like Karolinska could tie you up
也能让你陷入数十年的法律纠纷
in legal battles for decades if they have to.
你可能会破产 名誉扫地
That could bankrupt you, destroy your reputations.
届时你们的职业生涯将何去何从
Where would your careers be then?
天 这也太疯狂了
Jesus Christ. This is insane.
听我说
Listen to me.
他们故意把你带进来
They made a show of bringing you in.
你不跟任何人透露这点非常重要
It's very important that you do not speak to anyone- -
不能跟媒体说 不能跟同事说 谁都不能说
no press, no colleagues, no one.
我跟你说话呢 内森
I'm talking to you, Nathan.
行
Fine.
你们二位得把护照交出来
You two will have to hand over your passports.
什么 不行 我不交
What? No, I can't.
-这也太疯狂了  -我得走了
This is insane. - I have to go.
我要回俄罗斯
I have to go back to Russia.
什么 为什么
What? Why?
尤利娅·图利克
Yulia Tuulik.
保罗跟我说他给她做了手术
Paolo told me he performed the surgery on her.
你现在不能走
You can't leave right now.
她喉咙里有个血淋淋的
She's sitting there with a bloody time bomb
定时炸弹
in her throat.
我得给取出来
I have to get it out of her.
然后拿什么替换呢
And replace it with what?
再做个气管造口术之类的
Another tracheostomy, something.
前提是他他妈没切除一个肺
Assuming he didn't remove a fucking lung.
她是健康的 我能解决这个问题
She's healthy. I can fix this.
你不能离开这个国家
You shouldn't be leaving the country.
那就让他们抓我吧
Then let them arrest me.
三个街区 三个街区 好吧
Three blocks- three blocks, okay?
时间很紧迫
You're cutting it close.
交印的截止时间是
The deadline to print is in like- -
讲真 珀西 我是个记者
Seriously, Percy. I'm a journalist.
我清楚印刷什么时候截止
I know when the deadline to print is.
拜托 好了 我还有两个街区
Come on. Okay, I'm two blocks.
你在东边还是西边
Are you east side or west side?
-西边  -真的吗
West. - Seriously?
就差过个马路了 快了
Just cross the street. Come on.
好 我到了
Okay, I'm here.
我到了 我做到了
I'm here. I made it.
确实
You did.
这个新线人 最好别让我失望
This new source- it better be good.
喂
Hello?
你看到这个了吗
You see this shit?
我怎么可能看到你看到的东西
How can I possibly see what you're seeing?
他们给我们下达的这个小通知
This little warrant they've sent out for us.
在多次口头警告后 这三位医生
”The three doctors, after various verbal warnings,
将向卡罗琳斯卡医学院董事会
”will appear before the Karolinska board
解释他们的研究结果
to defend their findings. "
我们被传唤了
We're being summoned.
要上法庭了
It's a fucking tribunal.
我们揭露了这么多 他们让我们
After everything we uncovered, after all the shit
经历了这么多之后 那个该死的屠夫
that they put us through, that goddamn butcher
还在外面草菅人命 而我们却要接受审判
is still out there cutting, and we're the ones on trial.
这不是审判
It's not a trial.
放屁
Oh, like hell.
你有安娜的消息吗
Have you heard from Ana?
他们应该是在监视我
I think they're watching me.
-谁  -不清楚
Who? - I don't know.
有辆车停在我住处外面
There's a car that's been parked outside my building
都停了一天半了
for the last day and a half.
内森 试着 冷静一点
Nathan, try to, you know, chill out.
冷静
Chill out?
现在 晚安
Now, good night.
嘿 伯特
Hey, Burt.
加梅里医生 近来可好
Dr. Gamelli, how are you?
你知道的
You know.
幸好我穿条纹衫很好看
Lucky I look good in stripes.
是 整个困苦经历我都听说了
Yes, I heard about the whole ordeal.
等你看到报告再说这话吧
Wait till you read the report.
他逃脱惩罚的那件事 真是疯了
The shit he got away with, it's nuts.
我不用读就知道这是个错误
I don't need to read it to know it was a mistake.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你该在局面更糟糕之前及时收手
You should retract before you make the situation any worse.
我让什么局面变糟糕了
What situation am I making worse?
我们整个职业生涯都献给了这个机构
We have spent our entire careers in this institution.
你我来到这里都是为了寻求更好的东西
You and I both came here to find something better.
而现在你的所作所为
And now your actions- -
没人再会把卡罗林斯卡当回事了
no one will take Karolinska seriously ever again.
我们的声誉 资金都会付诸东流
Our reputation, our funding will fade into dust.
你见证了耶西姆·赛提尔情况恶化
You watched Yesim Cetir wither away.
-你看到他对她做了什么  -这不仅仅是一名患者的问题
- You saw what he did to her. - This isn't about one patient.
这关乎到数百人的生计
This is about hundreds of people's jobs,
所有他们的患者
all of their patients.
真不敢相信你站在他那边
I can't believe you're taking his side.
他的立场跟我们一致
His side is our side.
你不只是背刺了董事会
You didn't just go behind the back of the board.
你把我们所有人都卖了
You blew the whistle on all of us.
你不知道我们发现了什么
You have no idea what we found.
现在这已经不重要了
Well, it doesn't matter now.
你掀起了轩然大波
You've caused an uproar.
不管你的报告揭露了什么 不管真相是什么
Whatever your report uncovers, whatever truth there is,
都只是这片嘈杂声中微不足道的低语
it's just a whisper up against all this noise.
你本该换种方式处理这事的
You should have handled this another way.
哪种都行
Any other way.
去他妈的
Fuck this.
什么事
Yes?
你好
Hello. Uh.
说英语吗
English?
说 当然
Yes, of course.
我想找尤利娅·图利克
I'm looking for Yulia Tuulik.
姥姥
Grandma!
是萨沙吗
Is that Sasha?
你哪位
Who are you?
我是她朋友 尤利娅的医生之一
I'm a friend, a doctor of Yulia's.
她在吗
Is she here?
萨沙 饿了吗
Sasha, are you hungry?
不饿
No!
我想跟尤利娅谈谈
I was hoping to speak with Yulia
她手术的事
about her operation.
想跟尤利娅谈的话
If you want to speak to Yulia,
那得需要一条通往天堂的电话线
you will need a phone line to heaven.
节哀顺变
I'm so sorry.
你看起来很吃惊
You seem surprised.
感觉其他医生并不是那么在意
The rest of the doctors didn't seem to care so much.
她走的时候痛苦吗
Was- - was there any pain?
我的尤利娅就没痛苦过
There's no such thing for my Yulia.
我女儿很强壮的
My daughter was strong.
她一直在抗争
She'd fight and fight.
但她喉咙里那个东西
But that thing in her throat...
能跟我说下事情经过吗
Would you mind telling me what happened?
她咳嗽 咳嗽的很厉害
She had the cough, terrible cough.
她吐出来的东西
The things she would spit up- -
蓝色缝线 黑乎乎的
blue stitches, blackness.
她的皮肤也恶臭无比
And her skin, it smelled.
闻上去如同腐肉一般
Like rotting meat.
她喷香水 擦各种乳液
She would spray perfumes, all those lotions,
却还是能闻到那些味道从她身体里散发出来
but you could still smell it coming from inside of her.
那是死亡的味道
The death.
那气管在她体内腐烂了
The trachea decayed inside of her body.
她只想给他唱首歌听
She just wanted to sing to him.
她的确唱歌了
Oh, she did sing.
的确唱了
She did.
萨沙
Sashal
我还想吃水果派
I want more fruit pie.
不行 你已经吃了很多了
No, no, you've had plenty.
你是不是困了
Aren't you getting sleepy?
暖暖内含光
May there always be sunshine.
我只睡了大概两小时
I only got, like, two hours of sleep.
你还睡了啊
You slept?
我曾经很喜欢来这地方
I used to love coming to this place.
抱歉 抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
我来了
I'm here.
谢谢你
Thank you.
尤利娅怎么样了
Yulia?
2014年10月4日
The allegations against Dr. Macchiarini,
由加梅里 拉斯布雷和斯文森医生
as outlined in the report dated October 4, 2014,
呈交给本会的报告上
and submitted to this board
针对马基亚里尼医生的指控
by doctors Gamelli, Lasbrey, and Svensson,
本质上极其严重
are serious in nature.
在卡罗林斯卡 我们的声誉不言自明
At Karolinska, our reputation speaks for itself
也必须无可指摘
and must be above reproach.
因此 对于学术行为不端的指控
As such, any claim of scientific misconduct
必须在最严格的条件下
must be evaluated and considered
进行评估和考量
in the strictest possible terms.
医生们 你们可以继续了
Doctors, you may proceed.
你们对该报告有什么具体的
Did you have any specific questions or concerns
问题或担忧
about the report or- -
可以说是本小说了 说真的
More of a novel, really.
有428页呢
428 pages.
都在上面写着了
It's all there.
大多数吧 无所谓了
Most of it, anyway.
我们呈交的其实已经是删减版了
We actually gave you the abridged.
好吧
Right.
那么 简而言之 有三位患者
So, to summarize, three patients,
都植入了马基亚里尼的生物合成气管
all implanted with biosynthetic tracheas
他谎称该生物合成气管已经
that Macchiarini misrepresented as viable for transplant
通过了测试
based on the claim that these organs
但其实没有
had been successfully tested- - they hadn't- -
他宣称该手术过程有着科学依据支撑
and that the procedure itself was grounded in science.
并不是
It wasn't.
在病例莱尔斯先生
In the case of Mr. Lyles- -
也就是你 拉斯布雷医生操刀的手术
Whose transplant you performed, Dr. Lasbrey.
的确是我协助手术
I assisted, yes.
你也协助过贝耶恩先生的手术
You also assisted at Mr. Beyenes'surgery.
-是这样吗  -是的
- Is that correct? - That is correct.
还有赛提尔女士的手术
As well as that of Ms. Cetir.
如果询问在场所有人
If we want to go around the room,
我想我们都能一致同意
I think we can agree that all of us
我们所有人都对马基亚里尼医生
bear some degree of responsibility
为虎作伥负有一定责任 难道不是吗
for aiding and abetting Dr. Macchiarini, no?
贝耶恩先生的成功移植
Mr. Beyenes' successful transplant
是发表在《柳叶刀》上一篇重要研究论文
was the focus of a prominent research paper
着眼的焦点 对吗
published in"The Lancet"?
是的
Correct.
而在座的斯文森医生
Of which you, Dr. Svensson,
和拉斯布雷医生是合著者
and Dr. Lasbrey were coauthors,
这份研究被列为再生研究领域中
ranked one of the ten most important studies
十大重要研究之一
in regenerative research.
这份成就着实瞩目
That's quite the achievement.
你还有多少反问句要说
Any other rhetorical questions?
我认为很有趣的是
I find it interesting that none of you
直到现在你们都没有一个人
voiced your reservations
对马基亚里尼医生的工作持保留意见
about Dr. Macchiarini's work until now.
我有啊
I did.
是的 加梅里医生
Yes, Dr. Gamelli.
你跟马基亚里尼医生的个人恩怨
We're all aware of your personal misgivings
我们早有耳闻
towards Dr. Macchiarini.
你恐怕你知道的连一半都没有
I doubt you're aware of the half of it.
我们都被马基亚里尼所误导
We were all led to believe that Dr. Macchiarini's work,
认为他的工作虽是试验性的
though experimental, was substantiated
但却经过了合法研究证实
in legitimate research.
置身事外来看 你们似乎是
From an outside perspective, it may appear
决定要受益于马基亚里尼医生
that you chose to benefit from Dr. Macchiarini's
的名誉和成就
reputation and achievements
直到你们无法再从中获利
until it no longer served your interests.
不管从何种角度看 这个家伙
From any perspective, the man falsified
都是故意在捏造事实
information knowingly.
他把疯狂的幻想打造成科学的理论
He misrepresented delusions of grandeur as scientific theory.
他对病人撒谎
He lied to his patients.
我们为什么要讨论其他事情
Why are we talking about anything else here?
我不是医生 因此原谅我的无知
I'm not a doctor, so please forgive my ignorance.
但就我的理解 那些病人
But it's my understanding that these patients
都已病入膏肓
were terminally ill.
如果有希望 虽然渺茫
If there was hope, however slight,
手术也给了他们生的希望
that the procedure gave them a chance to survive,
尝试一下又有什么害处呢
what was the harm in trying?
门格勒也是这样想的
Mengele felt the same way.
病患都同意进行手术
The patients agreed to these procedures.
他们受到了虚假信息的诱导
Under false pretenses.
他们都清楚手术有风险
They were aware of the risks involved.
不 他们不知道 他们不可能知道
No, they weren't. They couldn't have been.
听着 底线在于
Look, the bottom line is,
这些试验性治疗方法
these were experimental treatments approved for use
都是通过了同情关怀法的
through compassionate care laws in the service
目的是为了拯救生命
of saving lives.
院长 那你的底线又是什么
And how did that bottom line work out for you, Provost?
如果不符合伦理规范
It doesn't matter if a surgery
手术是否是试验性的都无所谓了
is experimental or not if you don't have ethical approval,
而他并不符合
which he didn't.
使用TGF Beta-3本身就是犯罪
The use of TGF Beta- 3, in itself, is criminal.
什么是TGF Beta-3
TGF Beta- 3?
马基亚里尼医生在他的干细胞配方中
The cytokine compound Dr. Macchiarini deployed
使用的细胞因子化合物
in his stem cell formulation.
我记得有一节就是专门讲这个的
There's a section dedicated to it, I believe,
大概在140或150页吧
around page 140, 150?
-155页  -155页
155. - 155.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
他们连读都没读
They haven't read it.
我们真的试图保持专业度
You know, we really did try to keep this professional.
专业度
Professional?
你被指控违反
You've been accused of violating
医患保密协议 泄露保密信息
doctor- patient confidentiality, sharing privileged information.
保持专业度是我们的报告
Professional by focusing our report
仅限于马基亚里尼在卡罗林斯卡的病患
only to include Macchiarini's patients at Karolinska.
还是你觉得只有这三个人
Or did you think there were only three?
凯西亚·肖顿 20岁
Keziah Shorten, 20 years old.
在伦敦接受尸体器官移植
She died six months after receiving
六个月后死亡
a cadaveric transplant in London- -
窒息而死
choked to death.
保罗就是用她作为
She's the one that Paolo used
自己在这里一切工作的例证
to justify all of his work here.
多谢你 加梅里医生
Thank you, Dr. Gamelli.
现在不是说这个的时候
This is hardly the time or the place to- -
然后就是他的杰作
Then we get into his greatest hits.
安德·贝耶恩 他的器官在体内腐烂了
Ande Beyene, his trachea rotted inside of him.
然后克里斯托弗·莱尔斯 他来到这里时
Then Christopher Lyles- he had six months
还剩六个月的生命
to live when he arrived.
手术成功的让他的预期寿命减了半
We cut that luxurious prognosis in half.
然后马基亚里尼出发去了美国
Then Macchiarini heads off to the U. S.
他用这些手术病例
where he uses these surgeries
请求食品药品管理局批准他
to ask the FDA to give him approval to operate
在芝加哥为汉娜·沃伦动手术
on Hannah Warren in Chicago.
你应该在电视上见过她
You'd recognize her from the TV.
她才两岁 从出生起就没离开过医院病床
She was two years old, never left her hospital bed.
你说完了吗
Are you finished?
不 要他还没停手 我就没说完
No, he's not finished, so neither am I.
我们张开双臂欢迎他回到卡罗林斯卡
We welcome him back to Karolinska with open arms,
他在这里将屠刀伸向了耶西姆·塞提尔
where he proceeds to butcher Yesim Cetir,
一个22岁的年轻人
22 years old.
她现在在美国 命悬一线
She's in the U. S. now, holding on to life by a thread.
还有他在全球犯下的罪孽
Then the global expansion.
在俄国为尤利娅·图利克动了手术
He operates on Yulia Tuulik in Russia.
她还有个儿子
She had a son.
他眼睁睁的看着母亲咳出塑料管和腐烂的肉
He watched her coughing up rotting plastic and flesh
然后死在了上周
until she died last week.
他却逃脱了法律的制裁
And he got away with it.
他逃脱法网 只因为那些植入物
He got away with it because it took time
腐坏是需要时间的
for these implants to fail.
他逃脱法网 是因为他预示着
He got away with it because he promised money
金钱 声望和诺贝尔奖
and prestige and a Nobel.
他逃脱法网 是因为我们视而不见
He got away with it because we let him.
我们很容易忘记做病人是种什么感受
It's easy for us to forget what it's like to be a patient.
想象一下你22岁的年纪 脖子上顶着一个大洞
Imagine you're 22 with a hole in your neck,
或是你的孩子无法自主呼吸
or your kid can't breathe on her own,
或是癌症晚期
or the cancer is terminal.
你求助于医生 你那时
And so you go to the doctor, and you're just- -
绝望而又脆弱
you're desperate and vulnerable,
只想有人能够告诉你该怎么做
and you're just looking for someone to tell you what to do.
患者相信我们是因为我们发下誓死守护他们的诺言
And they trust us because we take an oath to protect them.
其中也包括让他们知道真相
Part of that includes telling them the truth
我们都希望看到奇迹
because we all want to believe a miracle is possible.
他在病患身上看到了这一点
But he saw that in his patients,
而他却利用这一点来谋私利
and he took advantage of it.
他给了他们希望
He gave them hope.
他向患者兜售新生命的承诺
He sold them the promise of a new life, and.
他们相信了他
They trusted him.
现在他们却死了
And now they're dead.
这个人在人类身上做实验
The man experimented on human beings!
他违反了所有医学伦理准则
He violated every principle of medical ethics
以及我们受法律保障的人格尊严
and human decency for which we have laws,
事情走到这一步 我们全都有责任
and we're all to blame.
我们本可以做更多的 包括我
We all could have done more, including me.
可现在 我们没时间做自我反省了
But, right now, we don't have time to soul search
因为他还逍遥法外 在手术台上行医
because he's still out there practicing medicine.
所以为了我们的病人和我们自己
And so we owe it to our patients and to ourselves
我们都要让他付出应有的代价
to hold that man accountable.
不然的话 我们没资格自己叫医生
Otherwise, none of us deserve to call ourselves doctors.
-我们走走吧  -去你那儿吗
Should we just walk? - To yours?
只要不是这儿就好
Any fucking place but here.
医生们 我想和你们说句话
Doctors, a word.
听着 这一路显然走的很艰难
Look, this has certainly gone quite a ways.
但路上仍旧有着岔路口
But there are still forks in the road.
你跟我们打什么哑谜呢
Why the fuck are you talking in riddles?
好吧 你们肯定看过马基亚里尼医生
Okay, look, I'm sure you've read Dr. Macchiarini's
对你们报告的回应了
response to your report.
错误已经铸成了吗
Were mistakes made?
或许
Possibly.
但还有路可退
But there is still a way out.
论文能被撤回 诊断也可以推翻
Look, papers get retracted, diagnoses reversed,
调查也会撤回
inquiries withdrawn.
那另一种选择呢
And the alternative?
就算董事会最终决定
Well, in the unlikely event that the board chooses not
不采取法律行动
to press charges.
没有了这个机构的支持
without the support of the institution,
没有了科研拨款
without funding,
你们想过这会对对事业造成什么影响吗
do you understand what would happen to your careers?
你们自己决定吧
It's up to you.
我曾想当个战斗机飞行员
I wanted to be a fighter pilot.
-真的吗  -嗯
Really? - Mm- hmm.
我内心有种渴望 对速度的渴望
I felt a need, a need for speed.
我想要开家面包店
I wanted a bakeshop.
你还会烘焙
Do you bake?
不 不会
No, no.
我不会 但我前任会
Not me, my ex.
她会做些 呃 那种
She would make- - oh, the things.
叫什么来着
The things, what do you call them?
她做过大黄 西番莲 抹茶味道的
She made rhubarb, passionfruit, matcha.
天 大家管它叫啥来着
Oh, fuck, what do you call them?
总之 她负责烘焙 我负责管理
Anyway, she would bake, and I would manage,
谁知道啥意思
whatever that means.
但命运给我开了个玩笑
But as fate would have it,
安娜·拉斯布雷 欢迎来到牛津
"Ana Lasbrey, welcome to Oxford. "
我想当个摇滚明星
I wanted to be a rock star.
我们知道
both: We know.
马卡龙 对那些东西叫马卡龙
Macarons, that's what they're called.
啊 超好吃的
Ah. - Oh, so delicious.
也许我该联系她
I should call her.
你最好还是不要联系她了
Uh...I don't think you should call her.
不吗
No?
归根结底
And at the end of the day,
这一切的意义是什么
what was the point of any of it?
上牛津 住院医生 实习期
Oxford, residencies, internships,
奖学金 学生贷款 早餐还得吃泡面
scholarships, student loans, fucking ramen for breakfast- -
客观来说 学医太苦了
I mean, it is, objectively, a miserable line of work,
然而
and yet- -
让人不禁思考 我们选择当医生
It's impossible not to wonder what it says
到底是为了什么
about us to choose it.
焦虑 48小时轮班
The anxiety, the 48- hour shifts,
没有一丁点社交生活
the utter absence of a social life.
是啊 但看看我们现在
Ah, yes, but look at us now,
站在历史正确的那边 问心无愧
on the right side of history, a clear conscience,
失业潦倒
and so extremely unemployed.
一群被炒了鱿鱼的
The unemployed.
什么 炒 炒
What? Shelabetsh- -
一群被炒了鱿鱼的
The unemployed.
-炒鱿鱼  -超有鱼
Albet- - - De arbetslosa.
炒鱿鱼
The arbetslosa.
妈的
Oh, fuck.
做对的事怎么就这么难
Why is it so hard to do the right thing?
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
回家 收拾行李
Home, to pack.
这已经没我好留恋的了 对吧
There's nothing keeping me here, is there?
反正
Anyway
我再也不想见到你们这些人了
It's not like I ever want to see you people again.
瞎说 你爱我们
Nonsense, you love us.
想来挺有趣
You know, it's funny.
我还在想 咱们怎么就没人问问呢
I was wondering when one of us was gonna ask.
问什么
Ask what?
马基亚里尼他妈的在哪
Where the fuck is Macchiarini?
是排了移植手术吗
Was there a transplant scheduled?
是的 这还用问
Yes. Obviously.
抱歉 我没意识到我们要
I'm sorry, I wasn't aware we were.
我是不是要去准备生物培养皿
Was I supposed to prepare the bioreactor?
我不需要生物培养
I don't need the biology reaction.
一会儿我们再聊 好吗
We will give talk after, yes?
也许英语更容易沟通
Maybe English is easier.
我不知道我们有安排手术
I wasn't aware we had an operation scheduled.
对 我今天要植入一个生物合成气管
Da, I'm implanting a biosynthetic trachea today.
但我并没有准备
But I haven't prepared- -
我自己准备了气管
I prepared the trachea myself.
我需要你专注在扩充品类上
I need you to keep working on the catalog expansion,
新的器官
the new organs.
这项工作当然在继续
Of course, the work is happening.
但出了尤利娅小姐的事 也许我们可以等等
But I thought we might wait after Miss Yulia.
我们进度已经落后了
We're falling behind schedule.
要想获得额外的资金
We need a breakthrough if we want
我们必须做出突破
to secure additional funding.
有个德国电视台要来拍专题节目
There is a German TV crew filming a special here.
等世界看到我们的成绩后
When the world sees what we're doing-
奇迹
"Miracles. "
完全正确
Exactly.
奇迹
Miracles.
你不是还有工作要做吗
Don't you have work to complete?
是的 先生 当然
Yes, sir. Of course.
所以想象一下 你不用再花上几个月或几年
So imagine if, instead of waiting for months or years
等待器官捐赠 你只需走进超市说
for someone to donate an organ, you go to the supermarket
可以给我一个新肝脏吗
and say, hey, can I have a new liver?
-不可思议的  -是吧
- Incredible. - Yeah.
这是前无古人的成就 这就是未来
It's never been done before. It's the future.
所以 你们在给身体制造零件
So you are creating new body parts?
是的
Yes.
对对 就像科学怪人
Yeah, yeah, like Dr. Frankenstein.
或是上帝
Or God.
所以
So...
这一次好多了吧
lt doesn't get better than that, huh?
非常好 保罗
That's great, Paolo.
播出去效果会很好的
That's going to play beautifully.
太好了
Ah, wonderful.
要不要拍个我从店里走出去的镜头
Should we get a shot of me leaving the shop?
当然 很好
Sure, great.
从这儿走到那儿么
So- so- so from here to there?
嗯 好的
Mm- hmm. Okay.
好的
Okay.
我的工作并不容易
The work I do is not easy.
创新从来都不容易
Innovation is never easy.
但我相信 人类的进化
But I do believe that we don't evolve
总是充满了艰难险阻
from a place of comfort.
也许地球不是宇宙的中心
Maybe the Earth is not the center of the universe.
也许疾病是由细菌引起的
Maybe disease is caused by germs.
这些思想 曾经匪夷所思
Those were revolutionary ideas once.
我想改变大家看待
I want to change the way we think about how
人体修复的方式
we repair the human body.
这是我改变世界的切入口
That's how we change the world.
是什么启发你发明了如此革命性
And what inspired such a revolutionary piece
的技术
of technology?
我不知道
I don't know.
但回顾过去
But when I look at it- -
这是我们第一款模型
this was the first model.
你看到了吗
Do you see?
这是一个十字架
It's a cross.
当人被钉上十字架时 会窒息而死
You actually suffocate when you're crucified.
这一点鲜有人知
Not many people know this.
但人不能呼吸 就会化为埃尘
But without air, we're just dust.
也许这就是它的使命 我的使命 上帝的旨意
And maybe this is its purpose, my purpose, the will of God.
你觉得自己是受到了神启
You believe you were divinely inspired?
不不不
No, no, no.
但我一直牢记自己的信仰
No, but I do keep my faith in mind.
这么说你是个教徒
So you are a religious man?
是的
Yes, I am.
你知道吗 教皇会穿双红鞋
You know, the Pope has these red shoes,
我作手术时也会穿双红鞋
and I also have a pair of red shoes that I wear in surgery.
是我妈妈给我的礼物
They were a gift from my mother.
你妈妈一定很为你自豪
Your mother must be very proud.
我想是的
Yeah, I think so.
她会在家中放一幅圣卢卡的画像
She keeps a portrait of San Luca in her house,
那是外科医生的守护神
you know, the patron saint of surgeons.
外科医生 单身汉和屠夫的守护神 对吗
Surgeons, bachelors, and butchers, correct?
你刚提到 你的工作不容易
You mentioned earlier that your work wasn't easy.
我背负了这份医学重任
This medicine, I hold it on my shoulders.
要不停地把它往山上推
I have to keep pushing it up the mountain.
有些早晨 我独自一人在酒店醒来
Some mornings, I wake up in my hotel
家人都不在身边
all alone, away from my family.
其实 我一年中大部分时光都是如此
In fact, I spend most of my year like that.
睡在酒店不那么舒服的枕头上
And this can be difficult- - sleeping in hotels,
这种日子并不好过
on pillows that never feel quite- - you know?
但我永远把病人放第一位
My patients are my priority.
晚餐只能叫客房服务 有时甚至是迷你吧台的东西
Room service for dinner, sometimes just the minibar.
电视上的电影
Maybe there's a movie on TV
也许我听得懂 也许听不懂
in a language that I know, maybe not.
有时我独自醒来 不知自己身在何处
Sometimes I wake up alone, and I don't know where I am.
这会改变世界 上帝的旨意
This could change the world. The will of God.
是很困难 非常困难
And it's difficult. It's difficult.
我很难
It's difficult.
真的很难
It is truly difficult,
没人能真正理解 没有人
and no one truly understands that, no one.
不过说回到你的问题上
But, to answer your question, the work I do- -
我的工作容易吗
is it easy?
不 不容易
No, it's not.
但救死扶伤
But to save someone's life- -
是我的使命
that is my purpose.
你好 瓦尔特
Hello, Walter.
你好
Hello. Um.
今天的拍摄很棒 对吧
Today was fantastic, no?
对 当我们遇上点问题
Yes, but, we've run into an issue.
问题
An issue?
什么问题
What issue?
我们得推迟明天的拍摄
We have to postpone tomorrow's shoot.
为什么
Why?
我们会再联系你的 马基亚里尼先生
We'll be in touch, Mr. Macchiarini.
我们有麻烦了
查查你的邮件
昨晚一定有人带了瓶瑞典土豆酒 把大家全都喝倒了
We must have had a brannvin gnome in the house
last night. lt seems to have all been drunk.
我知道你这次没在想小白鼠
l know you're not thinking about rats this time.
没有 我在考虑你
No, no. I'm thinking about you.
对不起 威尔玛
I'm sorry, Wilma.
你说什么
Sorry?
我知道你不喜欢麻烦 你警告过我 你让我别惹麻烦
I know you didn't want- - you warned me. You warned me not to cause trouble.
但我就是忍不住挖呀挖 把我们都挖进了坟墓
But I just had to dig and dig. oo
and now I've dug graves for us all.
我押上了一切 我有可能坐牢
I've risked everything. I could end up in jail.
我让我们 我们的房子和家庭都陷入了危险
I've brought this down on us, this house, our family.
我
And I
我不知道如何扭转情况
I don't know how to make it better.
没有扭转情况这一说 亲爱的
There's nothing to make better, karlek.
看看我把咱们带到了什么地步
Look where I've gotten us
你把自己看得很冷漠一个人呆在实验室 远离病人
You think of yourself as disconnected, down in your lab, away from the patients.
那你一点都不冷漠
But you are anything but disconnected.
这些人被伤害了 不能为自己发声
Those people he hurt...they didn't have a voice.
他们需要有人为他们站出来 所以你出现了
They needed someone in this world to speak up for them. So you did.
你为我们的儿子创造了更好的世界
You are making the kind of world we should hope for our son to have.
你应该为此自豪
You should feel proud of that.
我为此自豪
l'm proud of that.
为你自豪
Proud of you.
所以 你觉得会是什么结果
So what do you think?
停职 吊销执照 还是死刑
Suspensions, licenses revoked, death penalty?
我觉得 我可能酒劲儿还没醒
I think there's a possibility I may still be intoxicated.
你们看到外面的新闻车了吗
You guys see the news vans outside?
什么车
What vans?
有点不对劲
Something's different.
那是谁
Who is that?
这是埃芭·布隆伯格
That's Ebba Blomberg.
-她是  -瑞典研究委员会的负责人
She runs- - - The Swedish Research Council.
好吧 想必很多人都听说了
AlI right, as many of you already know,
作为本次听证会焦点的报告已被泄露
the report that is the focus of this hearing
其中一部分内容被写在了新闻里
has been leaked, and an article referencing
于今早发布在公共媒体上
its contents was published this morning to public outlets.
由于公众关注的增加
Due to the increased public attention,
卡罗林斯卡董事会已经决定
the Karolinska board has decided
将调查移交第三方进行
to hand the investigation over to a third party.
布隆伯格女士和瑞典研究委员会
Ms. Blomberg and the Swedish Research Council
将接手以后的调查
will assume charge of the review from here.
我们开始吧
Let's please begin.
请翻到143页
Let's please turn to page 143.
143页
143.
有个问题 在未经额外测试的情况下
There was a question about the shift
他从POSS-PCU材料
from POSS- PCU to pure PET materials
直接换到了纯PET材料
without additional testing in place.
可能我酒劲儿真没醒
Perhaps I am still intoxicated.
刚什么情况 我们的报告被人泄露了
What the hell was that? Our report was leaked?
-他说泄露了吗  -什么意思
Did he say leaked? - What does this mean?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
爱 谎言与人体试验
"Love, Lies, and Human Experimentation:
明星外科医生的的真相
a Celebrity Surgeon Exposed. "
听听这个 文章结尾写道
Listen to this, near the end.
马基亚里尼受到卡罗林斯卡医学院
"Macchiarini has been credibly accused by a group
同事证据详实地指控
"of colleagues at Karolinska.
举报人的报告中显示
"A whistleblower's report details
马基亚里尼长期以来的学术不端行为
"Macchiarini's long history of scientific misconduct
导致至少两名病人死亡
"resulting in the death of at least two of his patients.
再加上他个人生活中
"Add these claims to the history of lies
一连串的谎言和欺骗史
"and deceit in his personal life,
我们不难看出 他是一个撒谎成性
"and we are painted a picture of a man
甚至具有反社会倾向的人
who is wholly untrustworthy, perhaps even sociopathic. "
我的天啊
Oh, my fucking God.
新闻车就停在门前
The news vans out front.
各大媒体都在关注这个新闻
Outlets are picking this up.
美国媒体
American outlets.
瑞典方面很愤怒
Sweden is pissed.
终于有希望了
Well, that's it.
你也看到里面那群人的架势了
You saw them in there.
他已经失去了卡罗林斯卡的支持
Karolinska can't stand behind him anymore.
我们成功了吗
Did we do it?
似乎是这个女人干的
It seems this woman did it.
贝妮塔·亚历山大是什么来头
Who the hell is Benita Alexander?
“还教皇”抱歉 这人全用了大写
"The Pope? ”Sorry, it's all caps.
教皇 她还真信啊
"The Pope? She seriously believed that?
有够白痴的
What a fucking idiot. "
骂得好
I mean, it's fair.
等下 这条不错
Hold on, hold on. This one's good.
这蠢妞是喝大发了吧
"Was this bitch drunk or something? "
-你觉得呢  -你就是
Uh, you think? - Yeah, you were.
-还有点疯狂  -疯狂又上头
And a little crazy. - Drunk and crazy.
每个人都有这种时候 对吧
We all got to be something, right?
当然 这条怎么样
Yeah. Oh, what about this one?
她怎么能让那种男人接近自己女儿
"How could she let that man near her daughter?
这种母亲真可怕
What a terrible mother. "
-好吧 你知道  -不不不
AlI right, you know- - - No, no, no, no, no.
我都还没
I'm not even.
劳伦斯回复你了吗
Have you heard back from Lawrence?
哦 不
Oh, no.
我收到回复了
I mean, yes, I did.
但我被拒了
It was a no.
真抱歉
I'm sorry.
天 你绝对是那份工作的最佳人选
God, you would have been perfect for that job.
是啊 但我会一直被拒的 金
Yeah, they're all gonna be no, Kim.
-什么意思  -所有报社都嫌弃我
What do you mean? - I'm un- hirable.
-别说傻话  -是真的
Oh, stop it. - It's true.
没人想雇佣一个跟采访对象
Turns out no one wants to hire a reporter
上床的记者
who slept with their subject,
更何况 我睡的那个人最后还是个骗子
especially when that subject turned out to be a con man.
黄金法则你是知道的
Oh, well, you know the golden rule.
别操（搞砸）你的消息源
both: You don't fuck your sources.
就该拿我的头像做个宣传语
Right, they should put me on the poster.
对
Yep.
你知道的越多
♪"The More You Know"♪
我知道 我的日子会不好过
I mean, I knew it was going to be hard.
但没想到会这么艰难
But some of this, I just didn't expect.
你这表现是后悔了
You getting symptoms of regret?
我这表现是在质疑
I'm having symptoms of wondering
一切是否值得 哪怕有一刻
whether it was worth it, whether any of this
是值得的 你懂吗
is ever worth it, you know?
站出来
Put yourself out there.
说出实情
Tell the truth.
妈的
Fuck.
做对的事怎么就这么难
Why is it so hard to do the right thing?
但你还是做了
But you did.
再看吧
We'll see.
喂
Hello?
对 我就是
Yes, this is he.
知道了
I see.
谢谢
Thanks.
谢谢你告诉我
Thank you for calling.
想好晚餐吃什么了吗
Do you know what you want for dinner?
吃什么都行
Whatever.
你怎么看那篇报道
What did you think about the article?
没必要装作不知道
There's no point in pretending.
网上都有
It's on the internet.
你应该看看底下的评论
You should see what people are saying.
我知道他们会说什么
I know what they're saying.
我也相信了他
I believed him too.
我一直在努力找出
I have been trying really hard to figure out
跟你解释这一切的方式
how to explain all of this to you,
真相是什么 他为什么要撒谎
what was real, why he lied.
但我觉得 这永远会是个谜
But I just don't think we're ever going to know,
我们必须接受这一点
and we have to be okay with that.
但这并不重要 因为只要你还在我身边
But it doesn't even matter because as long
我就知足了 宝贝
as I have you, kiddo, I'm good.
别人爱怎么说怎么说
People can say whatever they want.
你最后教训了他一顿
You kinda kicked his ass.
帮我们报仇了 不是吗
We did, didn't we?
是的
Yeah.
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
-贝妮塔  -艾莉森
Benita? - Allison?
-对 你好  -嗨
Yeah, hi. - Hi.
请坐吧
Sit, please.
谢谢你跟我见面
Thank you for meeting me.
不客气
Yeah, of course.
你的留言 有点含糊其辞
Your message was a little vague.
你找我有事吗
What can I do for you?
我是埃培智集团的广告主管 我工作很出色
I'm an ad exec at IPG- - a good one.
我善于洞察人心
I read people.
我能够预判公众潜在的喜好
I can tell the public what they want before they even know it.
然后推给他们想看的东西
Then I give it to them.
六个月前 我被我未婚夫
And six months ago, I was conned
骗了
by my fiance- -
前未婚夫
former.
我的大脑就像被一团迷雾笼罩
It was like this fog all around my head
所有的真相和谎言都交织在一起 直到
just wrapping up the truth and the lies until it all just- -
坦白讲 我当时一个倾诉的人都没有
I didn't have anyone to talk to, be honest with.
然后我读到了你的文章
And then I read your article.
你勇敢地讲了出来
You just told it.
直截了当 不畏惧仇恨者的诋毁
You put it out there, haters be damned.
仇恨者还真不少
Well, there certainly are haters.
谁在乎啊
Who gives a shit?
你掌控了自己的故事
You're owning your story.
读着你的故事 我有一种
When I read it, it just made me feel
被看到的感觉
seen, I guess.
这种事既然能发生在你我身上
Well, if it could happen to you,
至少证明也曾发生在
and it happened to me, at least we're not
别人身上 对吧
the only ones, right?
是的
Yeah. Yeah.
其实 你愿意让我
Actually, would you be interested
来讲述你的故事吗
in me telling your story?
好的
Yeah.
好啊
AlI right, yeah.
同意吗
Yeah?
同意
Yeah.
我可以录音吗
Is it okay if I record this?
没问题
Sure.
好吧
Okay.
那就
AlI right, so...
今天 民众聚集在一起
Crowds have gathered today to hear
重大新闻
等待瑞典警方对名人外科医生
the verdict of the Swedish Police investigation
重大新闻
保罗·马基亚里尼的调查结果
into celebrity surgeon Paolo Macchiarini,
他被指控医疗不当
who has been accused of medical misconduct.
官方希望今天能对这个
Officials are hoping for an indictment
在全球医学界掀起
to be issued today in the case
轩然大波的案件提出公诉
that has taken the global medical community by storm.
是我女儿
My daughter.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你好
Hello.
经过几个月的调查和审议
After months of investigations and deliberations,
我们 与总检察长一道
we, along with the Prosecutor General,
决定公布我们的调查结果
are prepared to announce our findings.
我们发现马基亚里尼医生
We have found that there was a clear and real
在瑞典任职期间
scientific misconduct that took place- -
存在明显的学术不端行为
negligence and surgical misadventures- -
包括渎职和手术事故
during Dr. Macchiarini's tenure here in Sweden.
然而 我们没有理由
However, we do not have the grounds
指控保罗·马基亚里尼医生存在任何犯罪行为
to charge Dr. Paolo Macchiarini with any criminal conduct.
我们的结论是 无法从刑法层面上
In our conclusion, in terms of the criminal law,
追究他的法律责任
there are no grounds for legal liability.
调查到此结束
This investigation has now been closed.
今天是星期三
It's Wednesday.
周中快乐时光
Hump day happy hour?
第一杯我请
First pint's on me.
第二杯呢
What about the second?
第二杯你请喽
The second is on you.
我不请 我请不起
I can't get it. I can't afford it.
第五杯我请
The fifth is on me.
我会回来的 肯定会一定会
"I'|I be back. "It must be, it must be.
我不知道 伙计
I don't know, man.
你觉得是什么
What do you think it is?
当里个当么 混蛋
Yippee kayak, motherfucker?
当里个当
Yippee ki- yay.
他对这种事很认真
He's very serious about these things.
千万别给他起话头
Please don't get him started.
-我同意  -不不不
- I'm with you. - No, no, no.
不要和我争论这个问题
Don't argue on this with me.
好吧
Sure.
他并没有胜利
He didn't win.
不算胜利
Not really.
不算吗
No?
但很高兴 我们做到了
I'm glad we did it, though.
我也是
Me too.
是啊
Yeah.
要是你能回到过去 真能找到一辆德罗宁
But if you could go back, if you found a DeLorean
你还能再做一遍吗
right now, would you do it again?
绝对做不到
Oh, absolutely fucking not.
但重点就在这里
But that's the thing.
科学从不完美 对吧
Science is not perfect, right?
远非完美
Far from it.
但我总觉得
But, for some reason, we think that
医疗体制可以做到完美
the medical system can be.
我们不能反抗体制 因为我们身处其中
And we can't fight the system because we're all a part of it.
所以 我想我们只能
So I suppose all we can do is this:
为完美而奋斗
fight for it.
这也是你留下来的原因 对吧
And that's why you stayed, right?
我想你说对了
I guess you're right.
你说的太好了 斯文森医生
Aw, well, that is lovely, Dr. Svensson.
好傻的发言
Such a sap.
我真 我真的受不了了
- I really- - I can't with this.
你觉得我是跟谁学的
Where do you think I get it from?
谁 我吗
Who, me?
-“我们要追究他的责任”  -不
- "We owe it to our patients"...- No.
“给病人也给自己一个交代”
"And ourselves to hold that man accountable. "
“否则 我们谁都不配
both: "Otherwise, none of us deserve
称自己是医生”
to call ourselves doctors. "
拜托 别这样
Come on. All right.
知道吗 有件事我一直想不明白
You know, there is something that's been bugging me.
我们一直很谨慎
We were so careful.
一直都是实体打印 那份报告到底是谁泄露的
Fucking hard copies- - who the hell leaked the report?
看来我们永远都不知道了
I suppose we'll never know.
就让我们感谢这么做的人吧
Let's just be thankful that someone did.
干杯
Skol. Skol.
Skol. both: Skol.
尽管他在卡罗林斯卡失去了特权
保罗·马基亚里尼博士继续在世界各地开展业务
在拒绝提出指控三年后，瑞典检察官改变了方向，对Paolo Macchiarini提出刑事指控，指控其与Yesim etir、Christopher Lyles和Andemariam Beyene的死亡有关。
他只被判一项罪名成立：
造成耶西姆·塞蒂尔身体伤害的重罪
他被判处两年半监禁
他的研究至今仍在使用。